<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Gifts With Humanity - Gifts With Humanity Blog</title>
  <updated>2016-04-11T13:54:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gifts With Humanity</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/150850183-bio-imaginarte-environmentally-sustainable-fair-trade</id>
    <published>2016-04-11T13:54:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-04-12T10:27:09-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/150850183-bio-imaginarte-environmentally-sustainable-fair-trade"/>
    <title>BIO Imaginarte - Environmentally Sustainable Fair Trade</title>
    <author>
      <name>Renice Jones</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Every year on April 22nd we celebrate Earth Day.  We talk about environmental concerns like global warming, maybe participate in cleaning up a nearby park or waterway, or at the very least think twice as we toss something that could be recycled.  But coming up with solutions to environmental concerns, particularly garbage, is becoming a much more proactive activity in developing countries.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/150850183-bio-imaginarte-environmentally-sustainable-fair-trade">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Every year on April 22nd we celebrate Earth Day.  We talk about environmental concerns like global warming, maybe participate in cleaning up a nearby park or waterway, or at the very least think twice as we toss something that could be recycled.  But coming up with solutions to environmental concerns, particularly garbage, is becoming a much more proactive activity in developing countries.</p>
<p><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Arturol-Mar-2010.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-549"><img class="wp-image-549 alignright" style="margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto; display: block;" alt="Arturol Mar 2010" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Arturol-Mar-2010-300x225.jpg" height="396" width="527"></a></p>
<p>In 2010, we met Arturo Buenrostro when we were traveling through San Miguel de Allende, a colonial town in central Mexico known by many Americans as a great place to retire.  Many Fair Trade craftspeople worldwide have artistic skills and choose to make products out of discarded material like paper, tires, tin cans, bottle tops, seat belts, etc. because the materials are readily available, less expensive, and gives the products a marketing story. It was different for Arturo.  His first passion was addressing the large problem of trash throughout Mexico.  He realized that the environmental issues in Mexico were a bi-product of poverty.  In his own words, Arturo explains his motivation and his mission for starting BIO Imaginarte to help address environmental issues and poverty in his country.</p>
<p><strong>What did you do before you started BIO Imaginarte?</strong></p>
<p>I went traveling around Europe on a very small budget and I met a person who followed anthroposophy, where one learned more about oneself.  When I returned to Mexico I  started to document enviromental issues and then I published two small books call reduce , reuse, and recycle and in 20 years I have sold 100,000 copies.  Then  I made a little book call the World of Composting.  I started in education because that's where you may have some results.  I went to give hundreds of talks about enviromental protection and then companies started to call me and I started to make programs for companies.  I taught how to make wells to save water,  how to grow your own food and some others.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the idea for the bags?</strong></p>
<p>My father is a graphic designer so I think I inherited observation and the ability to do things just by puting my hands on it.  We started to use garbage materials and give work shops to make all kinds of useful things, decorative things and toys.  We travelled around Mexico giving workshops on how to make things from trash. We put collection boxes in schools for the pop top tabs, which went along with the presentations I gave to the students.</p>
<p><strong>How did you start selling the bags?</strong></p>
<p>We start selling at environmental fairs in Mexico, then in 2001 we went to a fair in Nashville.  We sold 1000 bags.  We then started to sell with a man in Texas our inner tube bags.  We started to sell it in some shops and so we sold in markets and everywhere there was a opportunity to do it so we can support our NGO organization by making our own things.</p>
<p>I went to Texas, walking across the border with 100 bags, that I was allowed to bring into the US because of NAFTA, and deliver them to a man who would help sell them.   I then went to Cancun to find a market in European resorts, selling in boutique shops in hotels to tourists. At the same time we were finding shops in tourist towns around Mexico. I arrived in San Miguel  and began selling bags in five stores until we found the little space we have now.  I started to make contacts with people  in the US including Global Crafts.</p>
<p><strong>Who makes the bags?</strong></p>
<p>The first women we found who wanted to make the bags were in the state of Zacatecas where we were invited to do a workshop for women who did not have job.  The women worked from home supporting their families.  We would buy the bags they made.</p>
<p>The bags are now mostly made by five sisters who live in the town of Guanajuato.  They sew together the pop-tops.  One man, Chuco, makes the inner tube part of the bags.  They all work from home so they can spend time with their families.</p>
<p><strong>What makes you proud of BIO Imaginarte?</strong></p>
<p>What is interesting about our organization is that we have built something out of nothing, out of what is call garbage. Using our  own resourses and trying to be sustainable, we have create products that talk everywhere they go because they have become like a piece of conversation for many people so this is important for us. What is interesting is that we live day by day because we believe in what we do and we try every day to keep the work of our 12 people who work with us so they can have a way of living.</p>
<p><strong>Who are the artisans of BIO Imaginarte?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Julie-e1459197801970.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-546"><img class="size-medium wp-image-546 alignleft" alt="Julie" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Julie-e1459197801970-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Julie </strong></em>is one of five sisters that works with Bio Imaginarte. She lives with her boyfriend in San Miguel de Allende, working in Bio’s small retail shop three days a week and working at home making pop top bags the rest of the week. Julie said she wanted to work with Arturo because the bags caught her eye, and she really wanted to learn how to make them. Julie loves her job. She loves interacting with customers and making bags. Another job like her previous work in restaurants would be much harder and the pay much less, she considers this job a true diversion.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> <a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Emiliana-e1459197785702.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-545"><img class="size-medium wp-image-545 alignright" alt="Emiliana" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Emiliana-e1459197785702-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a>
</td>
<td>
<em><strong>Emy (Emiliana)</strong> </em>is another one of the five sisters working with Arturo, and has been with Bio for 7 years. She has three children and works from home, so she gets to spend a lot of time with her kids. She started off with Bio when a local charity group learned that she needed a job. They put her in touch with Bio, and she started of making small bags and bracelets. Now Emy makes specialized crocheted poptop bags. She says they are more complicated but more fun, and she earns more for them. A good day for Emy is any day she wakes up healthy and energized, but it’s a particularly good day when she can earn good money doing a job she loves in the comfort of her own home.<strong>    </strong>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Lola-e1459197819321.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-547"><img class="size-medium wp-image-547 alignleft" alt="Lola" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Lola-e1459197819321-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Lola </strong></em>is the youngest of the sisters working for Bio. She loves spending time wih her sisters and lives with Emy, so they get to work together. She like making the bags because she can listen to music and it is entertaining. She makes several kinds of bags, but she likes the Multi-color hobo bags the best. She’s been doing this work for four years. It’s been her only job, but she can’t imagine doing anything else. She hopes to go to the States someday; perhaps her work with Bio will take her there.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Mary-e1459197745593.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-543"><img class="size-medium wp-image-543 alignright" alt="Mary" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Mary-e1459197745593-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Mary </strong></em>has also been working with Arturo and BIO Imaginarte for about 7 years. She makes about 4 different designs including the Roxy Bags and the small Cellphone bags. She is a runner, and in her free time she is training for races or caring for her son and daughter. Mary used to work in restaurants, but when she gave birth to her daughter that work became very difficult with longs hours on her feet. She enjoys her work with Bio Imaginarte because she has more time to concentrate on her family and running, and she makes enough money to be independent and support her family herself.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/IMG_1607-e1459198453102.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-550"><img class="size-medium wp-image-550 alignleft" alt="IMG_1607" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/IMG_1607-e1459198453102-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Josefina </strong></em>is a dedicated mother of one and hard-working member of the Bio Imaginarte team. She started off helping her older sister Emy complete her orders for small pop-top coin purses, and has since then moved on to Serena bags and pencil cases. Arturo notes that her bags are exceptional for their tightly-woven stitching. With this work Josefina has time to dedicate to her children, as well as help her older sister care for her kids, as she works a lot. Josefina says this work as made her life much better, because she has time for her daughter, her family, and herself.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Chucho-Jesus-e1459197764874.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-544"><img class="size-medium wp-image-544 alignright" alt="Chucho (Jesus)" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Chucho-Jesus-e1459197764874-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Chucho (Jesus) </strong></em>is responsible for the construction of the bags that include inner tube. Chucho loves to work, he and his wife live next door to the school their children go to and are able to work at home and spend time with them when they come home. He likes watching soccer and going to the park with his family. Chucho used to work in construction, but his job was unstable and the work was demanding. He came to Arturo looking for a job, and Arturo gave him a pop-top bag, all the materials he would need to make it and told Chucho to copy it. He was back in two days with an identical bag. Chucho has a keen eye, and does most of his measuring for the bags by eye. The inner tubes are heavy and hard to work with, but he likes his job because he gets to create something outdoors in the fresh air in the company of his wife and kids.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Martina-e1459197836511.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-548"><img class="size-medium wp-image-548 alignleft" alt="Martina" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/Martina-e1459197836511-225x300.jpg" height="300" width="225"></a></td>
<td>
<em><strong> Pedro and Martina, </strong></em>brother and sister, create the linings in the Bio Imaginarte pop-top bags. Martina has been working since she was eight years old cleaning homes, taking care of families, children and pets in order to provide for her family, including her younger brother Pedro. Though she is passionate about all the work she’s had, sewing is her favorite. She got Pedro into her business after his bosses stopped paying him at the factory where he worked. The pair also make women’s clothing to sell in markets, but the work with Bio provides a steady supplemental income. The two work very hard, as often as possible. The money they make allows them to support themselves and care for their many friends and extensive family.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>                          </strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Click <a href="https://youtu.be/GOMhQuAR0OM" target="_blank">here </a>to see the video of the artisans. </strong> </em></p>
<div data-accent_color="7a7070" data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-cart_button_text="Cart" data-cart_title="Your cart" data-cart_total_text="Total" data-checkout_button_text="Checkout" data-discount_notice_text="Shipping and discount codes are added at checkout." data-embed_type="cart" data-empty_cart_text="Your cart is empty." data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com" data-sticky="true" data-text_color="000000"></div>
<div data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-buy_button_out_of_stock_text="Out of Stock" data-buy_button_product_unavailable_text="Unavailable" data-buy_button_text="Buy now" data-collection_handle="bags" data-display_size="compact" data-embed_type="collection" data-has_image="true" data-next_page_button_text="Next page" data-product_handle="" data-product_modal="true" data-product_name="" data-product_title_color="000000" data-redirect_to="modal" data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com"></div>
<script type="text/javascript">document.getElementById('ShopifyEmbedScript') || document.write('<script type="text/javascript" src="https://widgets.shopifyapps.com/assets/widgets/embed/client.js" id="ShopifyEmbedScript"><\/script>');</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/124715591-the-path-often-traveled-why-returned-peace-corps-volunteers-find-fair-trade</id>
    <published>2016-02-25T10:09:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-25T10:16:42-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/124715591-the-path-often-traveled-why-returned-peace-corps-volunteers-find-fair-trade"/>
    <title>The Path Often Traveled – Why Returned Peace Corps Volunteers Find Fair Trade</title>
    <author>
      <name>Renice Jones</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A popular T-shirt of returned Peace Corps volunteers says “Some see the glass half full, others half empty.  A PCV sees a shower.” It’s safe to say this unusual outlook on the world helps explain why RPCVs are often drawn to Fair Trade.  You might not be able to pick them out at the Fair Trade Federation conference because of their Birkenstocks and bad haircuts, but the desire to help people in the country where they served and others who are challenged with poverty stays with them for a lifetime and fits amazingly well with the Fair Trade principles.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/124715591-the-path-often-traveled-why-returned-peace-corps-volunteers-find-fair-trade">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A popular T-shirt of returned Peace Corps volunteers says “Some see the glass half full, others half empty.  A PCV sees a shower.” It’s safe to say this unusual outlook on the world helps explain why RPCVs are often drawn to Fair Trade.  You might not be able to pick them out at the Fair Trade Federation conference because of their Birkenstocks and bad haircuts, but the desire to help people in the country where they served and others who are challenged with poverty stays with them for a lifetime and fits amazingly well with the Fair Trade principles.  So in advance of Peace Corps Week (February 28<sup>th</sup>-March 5<sup>th</sup>), I want to take this opportunity to introduce you to some of the FTF members who served as Peace Corps volunteers and took the path often traveled into the world of Fair Trade.</p>
<p>Peace Corps started in 1962 and <strong>Bob and Sue Chase</strong>, joined as a young married couple right after college in 1968, during an incredibly turbulent time<a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/bobsuechase.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-394"><img alt="bobsuechase" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/bobsuechase-300x254.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a> in US history including the assassinations of Martin Luther King Jr. and Robert Kennedy.  Bob is the CEO of <a href="http://www.serrv.org/" target="_blank"><strong>SERRV International</strong> </a>and Sue has worked for SERRV in many capacities.  Early in his SERRV career, Bob attended the NAATO (North American Alternative Trade Organization) conference, the predecessor of the Fair Trade Federation.</p>
<p>With Peace Corps’ still trying to define itself and its programs in the 1960’s, young people were often unprepared for the political environment in which they were immersed. “As we struggled to be ‘useful’…we became increasingly aware of how problematic it is for people from the Global North to impact poverty in developing nations with traditional development approaches,” Bob said. “Without a doubt, the exposure we had during our Peace Corps tour to the struggles of so many people in the developing world framed our world view and life goals,” Bob said. “It also convinced us that we could have a greater impact on the lives of struggling people if we could help to provide them with training, employment, and empowerment support.”</p>
<p style="float: left;"><strong><a href="http://www.heirloomrice.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="maryhensley-mary_and_isabel" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/maryhensley-mary_and_isabel-300x257.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>Mary Hensley</strong> was a volunteer in the Philippines in 1976 through 1978.  Twenty-seven years after her service, she returned to the village where she lived with a feasibility study and a business plan for a Fair Trade partnership to turn their heirloom varieties rice, a crop that everyone in this remote mountainous region still grows, into a regional economic engine for the farmers. The Cordillera Heirloom Rice Project, with FTF member <a href="http://www.heirloomrice.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Eighth Wonder</strong> <strong>Inc</strong></a>. as its US-based marketing partner, now works in over a dozen municipalities across 3 provinces. The Rice Terraces Farmers Cooperative, which the project helped found, now has four processing facilities for heirloom rice and villages processing machines throughout the Cordillera. In 2015 the organization will be processing its 10<sup>th</sup> harvest for local and international sales.</p>
<p>“I had the credibility to walk into the village with such an audacious plan,” Mary said, “because I had been a Peace Corps volunteer and I had returned.”</p>
<p><strong>Mary Joan Ferrara</strong> set off for Botswana in 1989 to run a weaving workshop for people with disabilities. She has worked with the Guatemalan artisans <a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/maryjoanferrara-2-2.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-396"><img alt="maryjoanferrara-2-2" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/maryjoanferrara-2-2-300x272.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>of <a href="https://www.upavimcrafts.org/" target="_blank"><strong>UPAVIM</strong></a>, one of the founding member organizations of the FTF, since 1998.</p>
<p style="float: left;">“It wasn’t until I started working in my current position that I realized that everything I did in running my workshop was following fair trade principles and it was my life’s work,” Mary Joan said. “It was so instinctual to me for [the Botswana weaving workshop] Twelelopele to follow the core principles of fair trade. The artisans got a fair wage for their work in a safe and fair working environment.  It was very satisfying to help these people with disabilities become so empowered by their ability to help their families buy food and supplies and be productive members of their communities.”</p>
<p><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/damianjones1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-397"><img alt="damianjones1" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/damianjones1-300x205.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>While in the Peace Corps, <strong>Damian Jones</strong> became inspired by the artisans of the Kathmandu Valley and throughout the country. He also had always been intrigued by the use of glass beads in the Nepalese culture. Upon his return to the United States, Damian began to conceive the idea of working with artisans in a fair, dignified manner as a way to improve their lives. In 1993 and 1994 he took three trips back to Nepal to actualize his vision of “fair trade” as a path to sustainable economic and personal development for artisans.</p>
<p style="float: left;">“Though I worked in education [while in Peace Corps], I also saw firsthand the giant impact micro-enterprise made in the status of women and the lives of their children.” Damian said. “In a sense, putting together the observation of a corrupted, broken foreign aid system and the observation of the big effect of micro-enterprise, I came up with concept for <a href="http://www.aidthroughtrade.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Aid Through Trade</strong></a>.” In 1993, Damian began marketing in the US, joining NAATO in 1994 and becoming one of the founding members of the FTF.</p>
<p style="float: left;">Like many PCVs, <strong>David Goldman</strong> of <a href="http://www.atacora.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Atacora</strong></a>, found the spirit of service in high school that continued through his service i<a href="http://www.atacora.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="davegoldman-Boukombe-1-09-C" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/davegoldman-Boukombe-1-09-C-279x300.jpg" style="float: left; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;"></a>n Benin in 1992.  Earning a Master’s degree at 40, he “hightailed it back to Benin very well armed to co-create a market based project with some of the superstars I already knew there,” David said.  “Decades of aid-based development had left traces and improvements, but people were as poor as ever.  We figured that revaluing human and botanical resources by opening global and local markets would put money in peoples’ hands, and that they knew how they wanted to advance their own futures perfectly well:  having access to health care, educating their children and eating well.”  Atacora was started in 2010.</p>
<p style="float: left;"><strong><a href="http://www.globalmamas.org/" target="_blank"><img alt="International-Women's-Day-C" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/International-Womens-Day-C-300x183.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>Kristin Johnson</strong> and <strong>Renae Adam</strong> went to Peace Corps after college graduation in 1993.  The unlikely pair of volunteers fell in love with Ghana and the women that were their Peace Corps counterparts and started <a href="http://www.globalmamas.org/" target="_blank"><strong>Global Mamas</strong> </a>in 2003, with Renae returning to Ghana and Kristin setting up operations in the US.  Their story is the quintessential PCV-to-FTF member story that culminated in the pair receiving the Sargent Shriver Award for Distinguished Humanitarian Service from the National Peace Corps Association in 2014.</p>
<p style="float: left;">“The women of Ghana inspire us every day,” Kristin said. “Looking back over 20 years now and imagining ourselves moving to Africa as Peace Corps volunteers hoping to make a difference, we are instead so grateful for what we gained.”</p>
<p style="float: left;"><strong>“</strong>If it hadn’t been for my Peace Corps experience, I would have never been hired into the initial position when I joined <a href="http://www.tenthousandvillages.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Ten Thousand Villages</strong> </a>8 years<a href="http://www.tenthousandvillages.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="KCampbellRPCV2" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/KCampbellRPCV2-300x257.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a> ago,<strong> Kathleen Campbell</strong>, Villages purchasing director said of her PCV service in 2006. “Beyond that, yes, the experience of working in fishing villages for 2 years made it impossible to go on in my career ignoring the inequities of the global economic regime. In the Peace Corps, you live and work with individuals, families, communities and the ecosystems that have little power in the context of the global economy. That experience of humanizing the consequences of North America’s wealth and relative power, creates an imperative to find a way to at least do a little less harm and perhaps to be a small part of the solution.”</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.thesilkroadbazaar.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="andrewkuschner---scarfmakin" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/andrewkuschner-scarfmakin-240x300.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>Andrew Kuschner’s</strong> first PC assignment in 2010 in Kyrgyzstan was as a TESL teacher. But as he became immersed in the culture he changed focus to the Small Enterprise Development sector because he saw the need of sustainable income and the amazing skills of the Kyrgyz artisans, particularly those working with felt.  Serendipitously, the Smithsonian Folklife Festival invited eight PCVs and their counterparts to demonstrate and sell crafts celebrating the 50<sup>th</sup> Anniversary of Peace Corps.  Not only was the event amazingly successful, it enabled Andrew to see that there was a market for the products.  He started <a href="http://www.thesilkroadbazaar.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Silk Road Bazaar</strong> </a>after his PC service.</p>
<p style="float: left;">“Kyrgyzstan doesn’t have a very developed handmade business sector, English language skills are almost non-existent, the red tape of politics is long, and there are many cultural differences,” Andrew said. “ I attribute a lot of the success of the business to the fact that Peace Corps afforded me the time to integrate with the people and get to work with them in a very profound and deep way.”</p>
<p style="float: left;">“I became interested in Fair Trade after experiencing firsthand how my talented and motivated neighbors in the village very often had no way out of the<a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/val-schade-mango-jam-with.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-402"><img alt="val-schade---mango-jam-with" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/val-schade-mango-jam-with-300x225.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a> cycle of poverty in which they were trapped,” <strong>Val Schade</strong> the Social Media &amp; Digital Projects Coordinator for <a href="http://www.tenthousandvillages.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Ten Thousand Villages</strong> </a>said of how her Peace Corps experience in Zambia 2010 through 2012 brought her to Fair Trade. “They grew corn, cotton, tobacco, and coffee, and their livelihoods were directly related to the market prices and rainfall. I started to remember all the times I’d thrown away a latte that was still half full, or bought a shirt on clearance that I never got around to wearing. I had been given the opportunity to get to know the people behind many of the things I took for granted in my daily American life, and I would never forget it. “</p>
<p><a href="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/renicejones2.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-406"><img alt="renicejones2" src="http://globalcrafts.org/wp-content/uploads/renicejones2-300x291.jpg" style="margin-right: 2px; float: left;"></a>And my story? Tired of corporate America and a more than a little concerned about being in the IT industry with Y2K looming, I decided to do something different and join the Peace Corps in 1999 and was part of the newly-developed sector that focused on computer training, including training a teenage mothers’ group basic computer skills in Kenya.  My focus rapidly shifted to include supporting the artisans in the handicraft sector by creating a web site with another volunteer and my now-husband, Kevin Ward, and selling their products internationally.  When we moved to the US and started <a href="http://globalcrafts.org/" target="_blank"><strong>Global Crafts</strong></a>, we had no idea we’d be working in fair trade with so many countries and artisans but we felt strongly that we had to make the online market available to as many as we could. In 2008, my PC counterpart, Philomena Mushaka who still works with the teenage mothers who make recycled jewelry that we carry today, made her first trip to the US to take part in the Fair Trade Futures conference in Boston.  I was thrilled for her to see what we had become as a result of selling dolls and jewelry the teenage mothers made and how the Fair Trade movement had grown.</p>
<p>While serving in countries around the world, we all saw firsthand that traditional aid did little to break the circle of poverty in our communities. Fair Trade as a term may not have even existed when we were volunteers or if it did, we may not have known about it.  But there is no doubt that any of us would have considered doing business in any other way, making the path from Peace Corps service to Fair Trade one that made perfect sense. We all know the Peace Corps slogan, “The toughest job you’ll ever love.”   In some cases it helps people find themselves, others find a calling, still others find a career.  But the desire to continue to play a part in helping those less fortunate by providing a sustainable path out of poverty is that itch that RPCVs need to scratch and working in Fair Trade is the near-perfect backscratcher.</p>
<p>When I reached out to this group, I was thrilled that so many of you were willing to tell your stories and share your photos and I don’t want to let the content I didn’t have room for to be for my eyes only. I’m working on a plan for what to do with this and will reach out to you before doing anything with it.  And if there are others of you in the Fair Trade Federation who would like to tell your PCV story for posterity, by all means send it my way.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/116062215-silk-road-bazaars-zooties</id>
    <published>2016-02-10T10:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-10T10:22:49-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/116062215-silk-road-bazaars-zooties"/>
    <title>Silk Road Bazaar&apos;s Zooties</title>
    <author>
      <name>Renice Jones</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[“Zooties®.” Is it just me or is the word almost as fun to say as these cute baby booties must be to wear?  Artisans and craftspeople in Kyrgyzstan have a talent for producing felt from wool and turning it into much-coveted carpets – why not make something else that takes up the space between one’s foot and the floor, even if it’s a tiny little foot?  Each time I think there can’t be another animal, vegetable, or mineral turned into a baby bootie, there it is!  Zootie lasagna!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/116062215-silk-road-bazaars-zooties">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img style="float: left;" alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Zooties-Fish_large.jpg?5919223843579325096" height="186" width="225">“Zooties®.” Is it just me or is the word almost as fun to say as these cute baby booties must be to wear?  Artisans and craftspeople in Kyrgyzstan have a talent for producing felt from wool and turning it into much-coveted carpets – why not make something else that takes up the space between one’s foot and the floor, even if it’s a tiny little foot?  Each time I think there can’t be another animal, vegetable, or mineral turned into a baby bootie, there it is!  Zootie lasagna!</p>
<p>Kyrgyz women hand cut, dye, and sew each pair of Zooties®. It is the tradition of felt-working that brings the skill to create the quality booties.  Available in one size for infants, the booties are made entirely of soft felt, with no buttons, snaps, or Velcro to scratch little feet. </p>
<p>The artisan project was started by a Russian artist in 1996, who focused on the design of felt products and providing Kyrgyz women with an outlet for their talents. Equipping Kyrgyz women with business skills including design, quality control, computing, and an understanding of the market was the project of a Peace Corps volunteer, who now, six years after his service, presents the Zooties to a worldwide audience through <a href="http://www.thesilkroadbazaar.com/">Silk Road Bazaar</a>. </p>
<p>Not only do the women have amazing skill turning the felt into booties, they also make stunning scarves, adorable animal baby hats, ornaments, mobiles, rugs, and new for 2016, sleeping masks, all from felt. It is a true example where tradition meets design.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><strong><a title="Shop Zooties" href="/collections/baby-booties-apparel">Shop Zooties </a></strong></h4>
<br>
<div data-accent_color="7a7070" data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-cart_button_text="Cart" data-cart_title="Your cart" data-cart_total_text="Total" data-checkout_button_text="Checkout" data-discount_notice_text="Shipping and discount codes are added at checkout." data-embed_type="cart" data-empty_cart_text="Your cart is empty." data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com" data-sticky="true" data-text_color="000000"></div>
<div data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-buy_button_out_of_stock_text="Out of Stock" data-buy_button_product_unavailable_text="Unavailable" data-buy_button_text="Buy now" data-collection_handle="baby-booties-apparel" data-display_size="compact" data-embed_type="collection" data-has_image="true" data-next_page_button_text="Next page" data-product_handle="" data-product_modal="true" data-product_name="" data-product_title_color="000000" data-redirect_to="modal" data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com"></div>
<script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.getElementById('ShopifyEmbedScript') || document.write('<script type="text/javascript" src="https://widgets.shopifyapps.com/assets/widgets/embed/client.js" id="ShopifyEmbedScript"><\/script>');
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/103951111-art-camp-artisans-tradition-builds-a-community</id>
    <published>2016-01-20T12:42:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-19T15:48:36-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/103951111-art-camp-artisans-tradition-builds-a-community"/>
    <title>Art Camp Artisans - Tradition Builds a Community</title>
    <author>
      <name>Renice Jones</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[The artisans of Tecalpulco, Mexico have long been known for their silver and stone jewelry.   Art Camp, short for Artesanas Campesinas (or rural female artisans), is a women-owned cooperative that continues this tradition.  The group constantly introduces new methods, materials, and machinery to compete in the highly competitive jewelry market, even surviving a collapse in the marketability of their pieces in the 1990’s  after jewelry from other countries flooded the US market.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/103951111-art-camp-artisans-tradition-builds-a-community">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The artisans of Tecalpulco, Mexico have long been known for their silver and stone jewelry.   Art Camp, short for Artesanas Campesinas (or rural female artisans), is a women-owned cooperative that continues this tradition.  The group constantly introduces new methods, materials, and machinery to compete in the highly competitive jewelry market, even surviving a collapse in the marketability of their pieces in the 1990’s  after jewelry from other countries flooded the US market.  The artisans have become business women, understanding the importance of  customer service, quality, and design. Their product range includes semi-precious stones, resins, and even tiny flowers captured in resin. Each piece is accentuated by alloys or precious metals, and represents the tradition of fine Mexican jewelry.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><img style="float: right;" alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/rubber-floor_large.jpg?1895331223833670984" height="191" width="399">Alpaca "silver" actually is a high-grade pewter alloy with the beauty of sterling silver, without the tarnish.  The artisanas carve molds out of rubber and fill with the hot liquid metal for the base of the majority of their pieces.  When the round rubber molds are retired, they're often used as floor mats.</p>
<p>The Art Camp pieces make up Gifts With Humanity's <a title="Artisana Fair Trade Mexican Jewelry" href="http://www.giftswithhumanity.com/collections/artisana-mexican-jewelry" target="_blank">Artisana </a>brand.  We want to introduce you to a few of the women who make the pieces we carry.</p>
<p> </p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> <a title="Berta's Mosaic Jewelry" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/search?type=product&amp;q=mosaic" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Bio-Berta-2_large.jpg?13983507751758395994"></a>
</td>
<td><a title="Artisana Teardrop Diagonal Mosaic Earrings" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/products/open-alpaca-silver-teardrop-diagonal-mosaic-stone-earrings-artisana"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/MJSED3_large.jpg?2949084810945848081"></a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Berta Dominguez</strong> and her husband have two children. Her husband was in a bad accident and is now wheelchair bound so it is up to Berta to provide for the family. Both her parents were jewelry artisans, so she learned her craft from them when she was young. She loves to take care of her daughters and help them at school, and working from home allows her the flexibility to take care of her family and still make a living. Berta makes the earrings that are the most popular design in the Artisana brand as well as the mosaic bracelets.</p>
<p>.</p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<a title="Maria Veronica's Mosaic Artisana Jewelry" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/search?type=product&amp;q=artisana+alpaca+earrings" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Bio--Maria-Veronica-2_large.jpg?13983507751758395994"></a> </td>
<td><a title="Artisana Turquoise and Lapis Teardrop Earrings" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/products/turquoise-and-lapis-tear-drop-earrings-artisana" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Turquoise_Lapis_Teardrop_Earrings_large.jpg?7825404973096916840"></a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Maria Veronica </strong>and her husband work together crafting jewelry. They have one daughter and had another on the way when we met.  Her husband taught her how to make jewelry when they married seven years ago. Maria is able to help provide for her family in ways she wouldn’t be able to without Art Camp. Maria and her husband share responsibilities taking care of their children and their animals, but Maria also does the cooking, cleaning and shopping when she’s not making jewelry. Working from home allows her to set her own schedule and set her own priorities.  Maria and her husband make the mosaic products including the long-teardrop earrings.</p>
<p> </p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> <a title="Marcelina's Abalone Jewelry for Artisana" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/search?type=product&amp;q=abalone" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Bio--Marcelina-Dominguez-Sm_large.jpg?3756487223481227322"></a>
</td>
<td><a title="Abalone Mother-of-Pearl Daisy Artisana Barrette" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/products/abalone-and-mother-of-pearl-daisy-hair-barrette-artisana" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Abalone_Barrette_large.jpg?8320994786410278346"></a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>  </p>
<p><strong>Marcelina Dominguez</strong> and her husband have three children. She loves to harvest her garden. Marcelina learned her craft from her parents and has been making jewelry for about 14 years. Her mother also worked with Artisanas Campesinas before she retired. She started at first just finishing small pieces, but now she is involved in every step of the process, from grinding down the inlay material to setting the pieces to finishing them with polish. She splits her time working and taking care of her children. Making jewelry gives Marcelina and her family more flexibility and allows her more time with her children.</p>
<p>Many other women in the community work from their homes, most using car or solar batteries to power the equipment they purchased. </p>
﻿​
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> <img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Berta-Working_large.jpg?13983507751758395994">
</td>
<td><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Marcelina-Working_large.jpg?4574832482144991581"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<div data-text_color="000000" data-sticky="true" data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com" data-empty_cart_text="Your cart is empty." data-embed_type="cart" data-discount_notice_text="Shipping and discount codes are added at checkout." data-checkout_button_text="Checkout" data-cart_total_text="Total" data-cart_title="Your cart" data-cart_button_text="Cart" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-background_color="ffffff" data-accent_color="7a7070"></div>
<div data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com" data-embed_type="collection" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-background_color="ffffff" data-redirect_to="modal" data-product_title_color="000000" data-product_name="" data-product_modal="true" data-product_handle="" data-next_page_button_text="Next page" data-has_image="true" data-display_size="compact" data-collection_handle="artisana-mexican-jewelry" data-buy_button_text="Buy now" data-buy_button_product_unavailable_text="Unavailable" data-buy_button_out_of_stock_text="Out of Stock"></div>
<script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.getElementById('ShopifyEmbedScript') || document.write('<script type="text/javascript" src="https://widgets.shopifyapps.com/assets/widgets/embed/client.js" id="ShopifyEmbedScript"><\/script>');
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/102221575-gifts-with-humanity-a-happenstance</id>
    <published>2016-01-12T12:22:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T13:13:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/102221575-gifts-with-humanity-a-happenstance"/>
    <title>Gifts With Humanity - A Happenstance</title>
    <author>
      <name>Renice Jones</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you believe that things happen serendipitously, then Gifts With Humanity is certainly one of those things. The co-founders met in the principal’s office of Kisumu Polytechnic in 1999 – I was a Peace Corps volunteer and Kevin was a VSO volunteer; both were assigned to teach computing.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/102221575-gifts-with-humanity-a-happenstance">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">If you believe that things happen serendipitously, then Gifts With Humanity is certainly one of those things. The co-founders met in the principal’s office of Kisumu Polytechnic in 1999 – I was a Peace Corps volunteer and Kevin was a VSO volunteer; both were assigned to teach computing.  We both left careers in our respective countries (I was an IT professional in the US and Kevin was the head of computing at a UK college) but realized it was time to do something that might make a difference in the lives of others. </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><img width="343" height="273" style="float: right;" alt="Renice at Kisumu Polytechnic" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/computers_large.jpg?5691251402758543303"></p>
<p>Many people in our community in Kisumu made their living as artisans and craftspeople and asked us if there was a way to market their handicrafts outside of Kenya. The Internet was just becoming a place where people shopped so we created an ecommerce website featuring the artisans’ products.  When our volunteer service was complete, we relocated to Florida (Kevin said, “If I have to go to the US, it has to be somewhere warm”) and opened a retail shop in 2002 selling fair trade handicrafts, coffee, and chocolate.  The Gifts With Humanity bricks-and-mortar store still exists in the sleepy beach town of New Smyrna Beach.</p>
<p style="float: left;"><img style="margin-right: 5px; float: left;" alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/Joab_and_Kev_large.jpg?5691251402758543303"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">While in Kenya, Kevin often mentioned the term “Fair Trade” to me. When he finally explained that Fair Trade was a worldwide movement and not just a way of saying everyone in a supply chain should be paid fairly, we designed the mission of the business around it.  After a few years in business, we realized that building sustainable relationships with artisan communities in developing countries and importing and selling their handicrafts wasn’t all there was to Fair Trade; rather, we determined that we had an obligation to provide access to the handmade market for as many as we could.</p>
<p>So here’s where serendipity really gets going. We both happen to have strong IT backgrounds, have built relationships with artisans and craftspeople around the world, and have made a lot of friends in the Fair Trade movement worldwide.  Gifts With Humanity is the culmination of our desire so long ago to make a difference, our belief that Fair Trade is the way all international trade should be conducted, and our confidence that the handmade products we carry are the ones that you will want to wear, look at, use, and treasure.</p>
<p>I look forward to introducing you to the artisans and craftspeople whose heart and soul is reflected in each piece that they make and am sure they will become your friends as well.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/28322625-the-bat-shop</id>
    <published>2015-05-14T11:48:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-12-22T15:00:55-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/28322625-the-bat-shop"/>
    <title>The Bat Shop</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Ward</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="float: left;"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/prbatshop_769_large_large.jpg?12809855395660419991" style="margin-right: 5px; float: left;"><span>The Bartel Arts Trust, or the BAT Shop, is an urban-based community art center that is a venue and facility for skills training, promotion and exposure of disadvantaged and emergent artists in South Africa. The focus of the center is local arts, culture, crafts and entertainment that reflects the Zulu, Indian and Western heritage of KwaZulu-Natal. The difference at BAT is the grassroots, the experimental, the cross-arts trends and the innovation that is promoted at the center. </span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/28322625-the-bat-shop">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="float: left;"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/prbatshop_769_large_large.jpg?12809855395660419991" style="margin-right: 5px; float: left;"><span>The Bartel Arts Trust, or the BAT Shop, is an urban-based community art center that is a venue and facility for skills training, promotion and exposure of disadvantaged and emergent artists in South Africa. The focus of the center is local arts, culture, crafts and entertainment that reflects the Zulu, Indian and Western heritage of KwaZulu-Natal. The difference at BAT is the grassroots, the experimental, the cross-arts trends and the innovation that is promoted at the center.  </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/17698149-about-ilala-weavers</id>
    <published>2015-03-19T14:47:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T12:53:48-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/17698149-about-ilala-weavers"/>
    <title>About Ilala Weavers</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Ward</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="float: left;"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/ilala_large.jpg?15983472345661646054" style="float: left; margin-right: 5px;"></div>
<span>Ilala Weavers is situated at Hluhluwe within the province of KwaZulu Natal, South Africa. The organizations was established some 30 years ago, with a clear vision and objective of revitalizing and enhancing the age-old Zulu tradition of handcrafts, which at the time were in danger of being lost forever.</span><br><br><span>Today, Ilala Weavers helps over 2000 Zulu men and women, to attain self sufficiency, by working from their homes and therefore retaining their lifestyle and rich heritage of basket weaving and bead work, which has been passed down through the generations by Zulu crafters. Their modern counterparts today produce stunning works of art, sought after the world over. Each basket is completely unique, and an artisan may spend up to six months weaving a single piece! </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.giftswithhumanity.com/blogs/news/17698149-about-ilala-weavers">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="float: left;"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0805/5707/files/ilala_large.jpg?15983472345661646054" style="float: left; margin-right: 5px;"></div>
<span>Ilala Weavers is situated at Hluhluwe within the province of KwaZulu Natal, South Africa. The organizations was established some 30 years ago, with a clear vision and objective of revitalizing and enhancing the age-old Zulu tradition of handcrafts, which at the time were in danger of being lost forever.</span><br><br><span>Today, Ilala Weavers helps over 2000 Zulu men and women, to attain self sufficiency, by working from their homes and therefore retaining their lifestyle and rich heritage of basket weaving and bead work, which has been passed down through the generations by Zulu crafters. Their modern counterparts today produce stunning works of art, sought after the world over. Each basket is completely unique, and an artisan may spend up to six months weaving a single piece! </span> <br><br>
<div data-accent_color="767676" data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-cart_button_text="Cart" data-cart_title="Your cart" data-cart_total_text="Total" data-checkout_button_text="Checkout" data-discount_notice_text="Shipping and discount codes are added at checkout." data-embed_type="cart" data-empty_cart_text="Your cart is empty." data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com" data-sticky="true" data-text_color="000000"></div>
<div data-background_color="ffffff" data-button_background_color="f58505" data-button_text_color="ffffff" data-buy_button_out_of_stock_text="Out of Stock" data-buy_button_product_unavailable_text="Unavailable" data-buy_button_text="Buy now" data-collection_handle="baskets" data-display_size="compact" data-embed_type="collection" data-has_image="true" data-next_page_button_text="Next page" data-product_handle="" data-product_modal="true" data-product_name="" data-product_title_color="000000" data-redirect_to="modal" data-shop="aedev.myshopify.com"></div>
<script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.getElementById('ShopifyEmbedScript') || document.write('<script type="text/javascript" src="https://widgets.shopifyapps.com/assets/widgets/embed/client.js" id="ShopifyEmbedScript"><\/script>');
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
